Simon Peter Ndacha +254757153661 https://github.com/Ndac haSpn simonndacha@gmail.com

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Simon is a developer that is dedicated to improving skills through handson learning and development work. He has internship experience in
development work and holds a bachelor's degree in business and
information technology. Adept at mobile and web technologies, and
development works using python. Complex problem-solver with
analytical and driven mindset. Dedicated to achieving demanding
development objectives according to tight schedules while producing
impeccable code. Well-organized and collaborative team player with
strong communication and analytical abilities.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Programming Languages: Python(3 years), Kotlin (1 year), SQL (2 years)

New Features Development

Debugging and Troubleshooting

Software Solutions

Code Writing

Strong Communication and Interpersonal Skills

EXPERIENCE

February 2022 – August 2022

Bafunde Technologies Nairobi

Python Developer Intern

Partnered with team members to learn best practices in software design.

Sat in on design team and planning meetings.

Wrote clear, clean code for various projects.

Collaborated effectively with members of software development team and personnel in other departments.

Created interactive websites with software development department using Django frameworks.

September 2021 - December 2021

Uwezo Fund Nairobi

ICT Attache

Learned new skills and applied to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.

Developed and maintained courteous and effective working relationships.

Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.

Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently.

EDUCATION

KCA University ,Kenya

Bachelors in Business and Information Technology

September 2017 – December 2022

Google Africa developer scholarship

Associate android development

May 2022

PROJECTS

WhatsApp bot. https://github.com/NdachaSpn/WHATSAPP-replies-

bot

A bot to open unread whatsapp messages and send an appropriate response

Language used - Python

Image encoding. https://github.com/NdachaSpn/image-encoding

A program to encode messages in images and another to decode messages encoded into images

Language used – Python

Forex, Bitcoin price predictor. https://github.com/NdachaSpn/Forex-

Bitcoin-price-predictor

It demonstrates how one can use machine learning to predict future prices of items on the stock and crypto markets. The AutoTs library was used in this project

LANGUAGES

English

Swahili

REFERENCES

Provided upon request